More heinous criminals will show up.
더 흉악한 범죄자들이 나타날 것이다.
This team is always working very hard.
이 팀은 항상 열심히 일하고 있습니다.
But there still has to be someone preparing for what may happen.
그러나 일어날 수 있는 일에 대비하는 사람은 여전히 ​​있어야 합니다 .
We need you to take on a case.
당신이 사건을 맡아야 합니다.
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
그와 그의 아내는 2주 전에 집에서 살해당했습니다 .
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
주변에 현금이 있었지만 그는 손도 대지 않았습니다.
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
그들은 그것이 강도를 가장한 원한 행위라고 생각합니다.
What? It's clean.
뭐? 깨끗해요.
The victims were overpowered without any sort of resistance.
피해자들은 아무런 저항도 없이 제압당했습니다 .
GUNGOK-DONG FAMILY MURDER CASE
궁곡동 일가족 살인사건
A type of systematic crime committed according to a plan.
계획에 따라 저질러지는 조직범죄의 일종
Is this a way of expressing
이것이 표현방식인가요
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
범인의 원한으로 인한 감정
Hiking shoes.
등산화.
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
강남 수성동에서 온 제품입니다.
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
그리고 이건 종로 군곡동에서 나온 거예요.
They're from different areas but the same culprit?
지역은 다르지만 범인은 같다?
JINJUNG-DONG, GANGNAM-GU
강남구 진지동
There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
진중동에서도 또 사건이 발생했습니다.
You're not an investigator. Why?
당신은 수사관이 아닙니다. 왜?
Please. I must check the crime scene.
제발. 범죄 현장을 확인해야 해요.
Hey. Didn't you hear me?
여기요. 내 말 못 들었어?
I told you to get lost, you bastard!
내가 길을 잃으라고 했잖아, 이 새끼야!
Damn it.
젠장.
This is important.
이건 중요하다.
The victim was hit by a blunt weapon.
피해자가 둔기에 맞았습니다.
And the safe wasn't touched either.
그리고 금고도 건드리지 않았습니다.
The culprit went to different areas and his only purpose was to kill.
범인은 여러 지역으로 이동했고 그의 유일한 목적은 살인이었습니다.
This is the third murder.
이번이 세 번째 살인입니다.
It's a serial murder.
연쇄살인입니다.
HWANGHWA-DONG, JONGNO-GU
종로구 황화동
Hurry to the scene in Hwanghwa-dong.
황화동 현장으로 서둘러 가세요.
A senior citizen was murdered.
노인이 살해당했습니다.
Why did he suddenly start a fire?
왜 갑자기 불을 지른 걸까요?
He's never done that before.
그는 전에 그런 일을 한 적이 없습니다.
I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
아마 예상치 못한 상황에 직면했을 겁니다.
He either wanted to destroy unwanted traces
그는 원치 않는 흔적을 파괴하고 싶었습니다
or it could've been his trace.
아니면 그의 흔적이었을 수도 있습니다.
It's CCTV footage.
CCTV 영상이에요.
We got a shot of the back of the culprit.
범인의 뒷모습을 촬영했습니다.
Let's put out an APB.
APB를 내보내자.
You want us to do that with just the footage that shows his back?
그의 등이 보이는 영상만으로 그렇게 하길 원하시나요 ?
Are you suggesting that we give him a warning
우리가 그에게 경고를 하라고 제안하는 겁니까?
-that he could get caught? -That's correct.
- 잡힐 수도 있다고요? -맞습니다.
The only way to prevent him from committing the next murder is this.
그가 다음 살인을 저지르는 것을 막을 수 있는 유일한 방법은 이것뿐이다.
The footage shows a man in a black jacket walking.
영상에는 검은 재킷을 입은 남자가 걷고 있는 모습이 담겨 있습니다.
The police have identified this man in the footage…
경찰은 영상에서 이 남자의 신원을 확인했습니다???
Even after you put out the APB…
APB를 꺼낸 후에도???
-At least share the information! -Tell us anything.
-적어도 정보는 공유해주세요! -무엇이든 말해 보세요.
It's been over three months
3개월이 넘었습니다
and the police still don't have a single lead on the culprit.
경찰은 아직까지 범인에 대한 단서를 하나도 갖고 있지 않습니다.
The decision for an open search.
공개 검색에 대한 결정
Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?
이것은 경찰의 생명선인가 , 아니면 파멸의 시작인가?
Did he give up on committing another crime to hide?
그는 숨기기 위해 또 다른 범죄를 저지르기를 포기한 걸까요 ?
Or is he still planning another crime?
아니면 그는 아직도 또 다른 범죄를 계획하고 있나요?
You never miss a day.
하루도 놓치지 마세요.
We never know when the crimes will start again.
범죄는 언제 다시 시작될지 알 수 없습니다 .
We will catch him. Certainly.
우리는 그를 잡을 것입니다. 틀림없이.
What if the culprit changed the MO?
범인이 MO를 바꾸었다면?
What do we do then?
그럼 어떻게 해야 하나요?
-What are the police doing? -Exactly.
- 경찰은 뭐하고 있나요? -정확히.
They still haven't been able to catch a punk like this.
그들은 아직 이런 놈을 잡지 못했습니다 .
-I know, right? -Yes.
- 나도 알아, 그렇지? -예.
STABBED WITH A CAMPING KNIFE
캠핑용 칼로 찔림
FEBRUARY 12, 2004 SINHEUNG 2-DONG, YEONGDEUNGPO-GU
2004년 2월 12 일 영등포구 신흥2동
MILK
우유
DAILY CASE REPORT
일일 사례 보고서
VICTIM PARK SO-EUN
피해자 박소은
THE VICTIM WAS ATTACKED ON FEBRUARY 12, 2004,
피해자는 2004년 2월 12일에 공격을 받았습니다.
IN THE CHEST, STOMACH, AND SIDE ON HER WAY HOME
집으로 가는 길 에 가슴, 배, 옆구리에
It's so cold. Hey, it's warm inside.
너무 춥다. 안녕하세요, 안이 따뜻해요.
-You're early. -You're here.
- 일찍 왔군요. -너 여기 있네.
You got here so early.
당신은 여기에 너무 일찍 도착했습니다.
-Yes, I did. -It's freezing.
-그래, 내가 했어. - 추워요.
-It's really cold out, isn't it? -Yes.
- 정말 춥지 않나요? -예.
Inspector Song.
송 검사님.
Last week, I made a wish while looking at the first full moon of the year.
지난주에는 새해 첫 보름달을 보며 소원을 빌었습니다 .
What?
무엇?
It's been four years since I joined the team.
팀에 합류한 지 벌써 4년이 됐다 .
I really hope you can start
정말 당신이 시작할 수 있기를 바랍니다
talking to me casually this year.
올해는 나에게 아무렇지도 않게 말을 걸었다.
Hey, come on. It's been four years.
이봐, 어서. 4년이 지났습니다.
Woo-ju says it's his wish.
우주는 자신의 소원이라고 말한다.
Woo-ju, our universe! Can't you grant his wish?
우주, 우리 우주! 그의 소원을 들어줄 수는 없나요?
Was that a joke?
농담이었나요?
I'll start talking casually then.
그럼 담담하게 이야기 시작하겠습니다.
Really?
정말?
Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've brought it up long ago.
이렇게 쉬울 줄 알았더라면 진작에 꺼냈을 텐데.
I should've done this long ago.
오래전에 이 일을 했어야 했는데.
It took too long.
시간이 너무 오래 걸렸어요.
Are you playing favorites?
좋아하는 게임을 하고 있나요?
You don't laugh at my jokes.
당신은 내 농담에 웃지 않습니다.
But you laughed at his lame joke.
하지만 당신은 그의 시시한 농담에 웃었습니다.
He laughed because he likes me, not because I'm funny.
그 사람은 내가 웃겨서가 아니라 나를 좋아해서 웃었다 .
That's right.
좋아요.
You must be a snowflake because he fell for you.
그가 당신에게 반했기 때문에 당신은 눈송이임에 틀림없습니다 .
You're so mean.
당신은 정말 못됐어요.
Anything showing a similar pattern?
비슷한 패턴을 보이는 것이 있나요?
-No, not the same pattern. -Let's see.
-아니요, 같은 패턴은 아닙니다. - 어디 보자.
DAILY CASE REPORT
일일 사례 보고서
An assault case…
폭행사건???
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
I hope he has stopped.
그가 멈추기를 바랍니다.
Whatever he may be doing,
그 사람이 무엇을 하든,
we just need to do our job.
우리는 우리 일만 하면 됩니다.
We got this.
우리는 이것을 얻었습니다.
PROFILING (CRIME ANALYSIS) REPORT
프로파일링(범죄 분석) 보고서
Why are you going through the profiling report?
프로파일링 보고서를 검토하는 이유는 무엇인가요 ?
Hoping to find some clues.
몇 가지 단서를 찾기를 바랍니다.
Clues, my foot.
단서, 내 발.
Thanks to that idiot, Song Ha-young,
그 바보 송하영 덕분에
the police were criticized for being incompetent.
경찰은 무능하다는 비난을 받았다.
And now, the culprit has gone into hiding.
그리고 이제 범인은 숨어들었습니다.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Why do you care?
왜 신경쓰나요?
Oh, it's a record.
아, 기록이군요.
He got here less than 30 minutes ago.
그는 여기에 온 지 30분도 채 안 됐어요.
HWANGHWA-DONG MURDER
황화동 살인사건
Time is ticking, but we have no idea where this scum is.
시간은 흐르고 있지만 우리는 이 쓰레기가 어디에 있는지 전혀 모릅니다 .
-Oh, you're early. -Hello.
-아, 일찍 왔구나. -안녕하세요.
How have you been?
어떻게 지냈나 요?
Woo-ju, say hello before you step out.
우주야, 나가기 전에 인사 좀 해라.
Nice to meet you.
만나서 반가워요.
This case made me feel the need to study, so I'll be joining you today.
이 사건으로 인해 공부의 필요성을 느끼게 되었기 때문에 오늘 여러분과 함께하겠습니다.
Good thinking.
좋은 생각입니다.
-I'll be right back. -Okay, hurry.
- 금방 돌아올게요. - 알았어, 서둘러.
We'll get started when Woo-ju gets back.
우주가 돌아오면 시작하겠습니다.
-Take a seat. -You can sit here.
-앉아 요. - 여기 앉으시면 됩니다.
Professors.
교수.
There are so many scumbags in this world
세상에는 쓰레기가 너무 많아
that we've got lots of studying to do.
우리가 공부할 게 너무 많다는 걸요.
About the serial murder of rich seniors.
부자 선배들의 연쇄 살인 사건에 대해.
The weapon hasn't been identified yet, right?
아직 무기가 식별되지 않았죠?
No, not yet.
아니, 아직.
What causes that triangle-shaped scar?
저 삼각형 모양의 흉터는 왜 생기는 걸까요?
We've been checking
우리가 확인해 봤는데
every blunt weapon we can think of, but haven't found a match so far.
우리가 생각할 수 있는 모든 둔기 무기가 있지만 지금까지 일치하는 무기를 찾지 못했습니다.
The abrasion, hypodermal bleeding,
찰과상, 피하 출혈,
and laceration.
그리고 열상.
Also considering the depth of the dent, it's not a light weapon.
그리고 찌그러진 깊이를 생각해보면 가벼운 무기는 아니다.
Considering the weight and force, a steel hammer would be a match,
무게와 힘을 생각하면 쇠망치 정도가 맞겠지만,
but they're usually either round or sharp.
하지만 일반적으로 둥글거나 날카롭습니다.
And It's not easy to carry it around as it's long.
그리고 길이가 길어서 들고다니기가 쉽지 않더라구요 .
Captain Kook, I'm beginning to think that your guess may be correct.
국 선장님, 당신의 추측이 맞을지도 모른다는 생각이 들기 시작했습니다 .
It makes me anxious.
그것은 나를 불안하게 만든다.
That the culprit made the weapon?
범인이 무기를 만들었다고?
If that's true, we can't identify it.
그것이 사실이라면, 우리는 그것을 식별할 수 없습니다.
I've never seen anyone put so much effort into murder.
나는 누군가가 살인에 그렇게 많은 노력을 기울이는 것을 본 적이 없습니다 .
-I bought it. -It's so cold.
- 내가 샀어요. -너무 춥다.
Anyway, is the lady in that building okay?
그나저나 저 건물 아줌마 괜찮아요?
-I think so. -My goodness.
-그렇게 생각해요. -이럴 수가.
What if she'd died--
만약 그녀가 죽었더라면--
-That building. -Goodness.
- 저 건물. -선량.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Last night, a lady on the second floor nearly died.
어젯밤 2층에 있던 아주머니가 죽을 뻔했어요.
Thank goodness she didn't die.
다행스럽게도 그녀는 죽지 않았습니다.
A stranger followed her and stabbed her.
낯선 사람이 그녀를 따라와 그녀를 찔렀습니다.
She didn't die?
그녀는 죽지 않았나요?
She's still alive?
아직 살아 있나요?
Richard Chase was also abused by his parents as a kid.
Richard Chase도 어렸을 때 부모님에게 학대를 받았습니다 .
He wet his bed, committed arson, and abused animals,
침대에 오줌을 싸고, 방화를 하고, 동물을 학대하고,
which are common in serial killers.
연쇄살인범에게서 흔히 볼 수 있는 일이다.
He killed adults and children in a brutal manner.
그는 성인과 어린이를 잔인하게 살해했습니다.
He didn't hold a grudge against them.
그는 그들에 대해 원한을 품지 않았습니다.
Why did he brutally murder victims chosen at random?
그는 왜 무작위로 선택된 피해자들을 잔인하게 살해했을까 ?
Most murderers like him usually kill for their own pleasure and enjoyment.
그와 같은 대부분의 살인자들은 대개 자신의 즐거움과 즐거움을 위해 살인을 합니다.
For pleasure, not because of anger?
분노 때문이 아니라 즐거움 때문에?
That is the most frightening part.
그것이 가장 무서운 부분이다.
It means killing makes them happy.
그것은 살인이 그들을 행복하게 만든다는 것을 의미합니다.
Killing satisfies them,
죽이는 것이 그들을 만족시키고,
so they can't stop.
그래서 그들은 멈출 수 없습니다.
They become bolder, looking for bigger pleasures.
그들은 더 대담해지고 더 큰 즐거움을 찾습니다.
Correct.
옳은.
That's why he mutilated the body and practiced cannibalism.
그래서 그는 몸을 훼손 하고 식인 풍습을 행했습니다.
Sexually deviant killers tend to commit such acts.
성적으로 일탈적인 살인범은 그러한 행위를 저지르는 경향이 있습니다.
So Richard Chase's cases are often categorized as lust murders
그래서 Richard Chase의 사건은 종종 정욕 살인으로 분류됩니다.
and as sexual homicides.
그리고 성적인 살인자로.
Sexual homicides?
성살인?
That's right.
좋아요.
The way he mutilated his victims doesn't show a pattern.
그가 피해자를 절단하는 방식은 패턴을 보여주지 않습니다.
There's no pattern at all.
전혀 패턴이 없습니다.
He didn't know much about human anatomy,
그는 인체 해부학에 대해 아는 바가 별로 없었습니다.
nor did he try to study.
그는 공부하려고도 하지 않았습니다.
Right, and he didn't even bother
그렇죠, 그리고 그 사람은 신경도 안 썼어요
tidying up the scene.
현장을 정리 중입니다.
He didn't even try to conceal evidence.
증거를 은폐하려는 노력도 하지 않았다.
So we could say that
그래서 우리는 이렇게 말할 수 있었습니다
Chase's murders were unsystematic.
체이스의 살인은 체계적이지 않았습니다.
He chose his victims at random, and it wasn't premeditated.
그는 희생자를 무작위로 선택했고, 그것은 계획된 것이 아니었습니다.
And even when he was caught at the scene, he was very confused.
그리고 현장에서 잡혔을 때도 그는 매우 혼란스러워했습니다.
On top of that, he suffered from schizophrenia.
게다가 그는 정신분열증을 앓았다.
His cases were typical unsystematic murders.
그의 사건은 전형적인 비체계적 살인이었다.
We need a list of your psychiatric patients since 1999.
1999년 이후 정신과 환자 목록이 필요합니다.
How do you manage to stay stuck in the press room?
기자실에 갇혀 지내는 방법은 무엇입니까 ?
You're doing field coverage and writing all the articles.
당신은 현장 취재를 하고 모든 기사를 쓰고 있습니다.
I get your passion, but your juniors will hate you.
당신의 열정은 이해 하지만 후배들은 당신을 싫어할 것입니다.
Aren't we both used to people hating us?
우리 둘 다 사람들이 우리를 미워하는 데 익숙하지 않나요?
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Not me.
나는 아니다.
What are you talking about? Your juniors hate you way more.
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 후배들이 당신을 더 싫어해요.
So?
그래서?
Will you do it for me or not?
나를 위해 해줄 건가요, 안 해줄 건가요?
We have to catch the serial killer.
연쇄살인범을 잡아야 합니다.
You know we're busy.
우리 바쁜 거 알잖아요.
Come on. Don't be like this.
어서 해봐요. 이러지 마세요.
Of course, Mr. Kwak knows how busy you are.
물론 곽씨도 당신이 얼마나 바쁜지 알고 있다.
He files a report whenever one of his girls goes missing,
그는 딸 중 한 명이 실종될 때마다 신고서를 제출합니다 .
but the police don't seem to care,
하지만 경찰은 별로 신경쓰지 않는 것 같아요.
so he's getting all anxious.
그래서 그는 점점 불안해지고 있어요.
Good grief.
맙소사.
Hey, over here!
이봐, 여기야!
He's here.
그는 여기에 있습니다.
This is the detective. Say hello.
이 형사입니다. 인사하세요.
Reporter Im has told me a lot about you.
임 기자가 당신에 대해 많은 이야기를 해줬어요.
Hello, Chief Kim.
안녕하세요, 김 실장님.
I'm Kwak Man-hyun.
저는 곽만현입니다.
GIRLS IN THEIR TWENTIES
20대 소녀
You didn't have to do this.
당신은 이것을 할 필요가 없었습니다.
Come on. You two should meet.
어서 해봐요. 너희 둘은 만나야 해.
-No pressure. -None.
-부담없이. -없음.
Anyway, pretend not to know me when you see me at the station.
어쨌든 역에서 나를 보면 모른 척 해주세요 .
I always do. Are you worried I'll suddenly say hi?
나는 항상한다. 갑자기 인사할까 걱정돼?
Who knows?
누가 알아?
The one thing I learned while working as a detective
탐정 일을 하면서 배운 한가지
is that you should never trust anyone.
누구도 절대로 믿어서는 안된다는 것입니다.
-What brings you by? -Hello, sir.
-무슨 일로 오셨나요? -안녕하세요 선생님.
I haven't been here since the team was bad,
팀이 안 좋아서 여기에 온 적이 없어요 .
and it still looks crummy.
아직도 형편없어 보이는데.
Hey, do you have water?
아, 물 있어요?
-Water? -Forget it.
-물? -잊어 버려.
I can't tell if this is a killer's hideout
이곳이 살인자의 은신처인지는 알 수 없다
or a hideout to catch killers.
또는 살인범을 잡기 위한 은신처.
Are you here to pick a fight?
싸움을 걸러 오셨나요?
Hey, those red marks.
아, 저 빨간 표시.
What are they about?
그게 뭐에 대한 것인가요?
Today is the 154th day after the first case broke out.
오늘은 첫 사건이 발생한 지 154일째 되는 날이다 .
The 105th day since we put out the APB on him.
우리가 그에게 APB를 내린 지 105일째입니다 .
You guys even remember your families' birthdays?
여러분, 가족의 생일도 기억하시나요?
Leave if you're going to stop us.
우리를 막으려면 떠나세요.
Kicking me out already?
벌써 나를 쫓아낸다고?
Why else would the chief of the Special Crime Squad be here?
특수범죄수사대 장이 왜 여기에 있겠습니까 ?
Goodness. Are you a psychic or what?
선량. 당신은 심령술사인가요?
A scary wolf is roaming around inside the rabbit burrow.
토끼굴 안에는 무서운 늑대가 돌아다니고 있어요 .
We won't stop until we catch the wolf.
우리는 늑대를 잡을 때까지 멈추지 않을 것입니다.
End of discussion.
토론을 종료합니다.
Fine. I heard you.
괜찮은. 들었어.
Just be careful and stay out of Bong-sik and Captain Yoon's sight.
다만 조심해서 봉식 과 윤대위의 시야에서 벗어나세요.
You're the chief of the team, yet you always walk on eggshells.
당신은 팀의 수장이지만 항상 달걀 껍질 위를 걷습니다.
What? Do you not walk on eggshells around your juniors?
무엇? 후배들 주변에서 달걀껍질 위를 걷지 않나요 ?
Captain Yoon is one thing,
윤 선장은 한 가지,
but Bong-sik has such a nasty temper.
그런데 봉식은 성격이 너무 심술궂다.
I do too.
나도 그래.
What do you say? Should I go ahead and load my gun?
당신은 무엇을 말합니까? 가서 총을 장전해야 할까요?
That lunatic will actually pull the trigger.
그 미치광이는 실제로 방아쇠를 당길 것입니다.
That's the problem.
그것이 문제이다.
He's been on everyone's case with that temper of his.
그는 그 성격으로 모든 사람의 문제를 해결해 왔습니다 .
Still, we can't just sit back and do nothing.
그렇다고 우리가 가만히 앉아서 아무것도 할 수는 없습니다.
We don't know when the murder will start.
살인이 언제 시작될지는 알 수 없습니다.
It's not like I don't know that! Damn it.
내가 그런 걸 모르는 건 아니잖아! 젠장.
My head hurts.
내 머리 아파.
I'm leaving. This place is giving me a headache again.
나는 떠난다. 이 곳이 또 머리를 아프게 하네요.
Would you like some tea…
차 한잔 드릴까요???
Thanks for asking me so damn early.
이렇게 일찍 물어봐주셔서 감사합니다.
Why are you getting mad at that nice kid?
왜 그 착한 애한테 화를 내는 거야?
Goodness, taking your teammate's side?
맙소사, 팀원의 편을 들어주시나요?
Be good. I'm watching you.
잘 지내세요. 나는 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
So why were you really here?
그럼 당신은 정말로 왜 여기 있었나요?
I came because I missed you. Happy?
당신이 그리워서 왔습니다. 행복하다?
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
I'm sure you were here to nag me!
분명 나한테 잔소리 하려고 온 거야!
A hundred and five days?
150일?
Those stubborn wackos.
저 고집 센 괴짜들아.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Yoon Tae-gu of Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
서울지방경찰청 윤태구입니다 .
-I heard you have information. -Yes, I called.
-정보가 있다고 들었습니다. - 네, 전화했어요.
Hey!
여기요!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
What's with you?
당신은 무엇입니까?
We're detectives.
우리는 형사입니다.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
-I'm sorry. -Okay, fine.
-죄송합니다. -좋아.
Darn it.
젠장.
The train is approaching.
기차가 다가오고 있습니다.
Please step behind the safety line.
안전선 뒤로 물러나주세요.
Do you think we live with pointless anxiety?
우리가 무의미한 불안 속에 살고 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
It comes with the job.
일과 함께 제공됩니다.
HAN JONG-YONG, YOON JUNG-YOON
한종용, 윤정윤
-Gosh, it's pouring. -It's cold.
- 맙소사, 비가 쏟아지네요. -추워.
-Hello.
-안녕하세요.
-Are you two coming in? -Yes.
- 둘이 들어오나요? -예.
-Are you going out? -To the market.
- 나갈 거야? -마켓으로.
Look what you've got there.
거기에 뭐가 있는지 보세요.
This is really good.
정말 좋습니다.
-Anyway. -Yes?
-그래도. -예?
"Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?"
"이것이 경찰의 생명선인가 , 아니면 파멸의 시작인가?"
That one was harsh.
그 사람은 가혹했습니다.
It's true. What about it?
사실이에요. 그것은 어떻습니까?
Inspector Song doesn't show it,
송 경위는 보여주지 않고,
but he's already in a tight spot after he put out the APB.
하지만 그는 APB를 내놓은 후 이미 곤경에 빠졌습니다 .
So who on earth is this Inspector Song?
그렇다면 이 송 경감은 도대체 누구일까요?
One of the two people I respect the most.
제가 가장 존경하는 두 분 중 한 분입니다.
Behavioral Analysis Team?
행동분석팀?
The profiler?
프로파일러?
Yes.
예.
After what Inspector Song said to me on my first day,
첫날 송 경위가 나에게 한 말 이후 ,
I never regretted joining this team.
나는 이 팀에 합류한 것을 결코 후회하지 않았다.
What did he say?
그는 무엇을 말 했는가?
He asked me that day why I applied for this team.
그날 그는 나에게 이 팀에 지원한 이유를 물었습니다.
Nothing really came to my mind, so I immaturely replied,
딱히 생각나는 게 없어서 철없어서 이렇게 대답했어요.
"Because it seemed cool."
"멋져 보였으니까요."
And he said,
그리고 그는 말했습니다.
Do you know the story of the blind man and a lantern?
맹인과 등불 이야기를 아시나요 ?
Someone asked a blind man who was walking down a dark road
어두운 길을 걷고 있는 맹인에게 어떤 사람이 물었습니다.
with a lantern in his hand.
손에 랜턴을 들고.
"You can't see anyway. Why do you carry that around?"
"아무래도 볼 수 없잖아. 그걸 왜 가지고 다니냐?"
Why do you think so?
왜 그렇게 생각하시나요?
He wanted others to see clearly
그는 다른 사람들이 명확하게 볼 수 있기를 원했습니다
and not fall down while walking.
그리고 걸을 때 넘어지지 마세요.
I see. That's touching.
알겠습니다. 감동적이네요.
A lantern.
랜턴.
VICTIMS: HAN SEOK-HOON, YANG KYUNG-HEE
피해자 : 한석훈, 양경희
KWON HYUN-SOOK, 54, FEMALE
권현숙, 54세, 여성
Then tell me his name too.
그럼 그 사람 이름도 알려주세요.
-Inspector Song Ha-young. -Song Ha-young?
-송하영 경위. -송하영?
-Honey. -Hey.
-꿀. -여기요.
-Did you wait for long? -I just got off.
-오래 기다리셨나요? - 방금 내렸어요.
-It's raining a lot. -Yes.
-비가 많이 오네요. -예.
Can you put it in here?
여기에 넣어도 되나요?
-Yes. Thank you. -Sure.
-예. 감사합니다. -확신하는.
-Enjoy. -Goodbye.
-즐기다. -안녕히 가세요.
My gosh, why is it raining so much?
맙소사, 비가 왜 이렇게 많이 오나요?
I'm home.
나는 집에있다.
Mom?
엄마?
The receiver cannot be reached.
수신자에게 연락할 수 없습니다.
I'm sorry. I'm late.
죄송합니다. 나는 늦었다.
Why didn't you pick up your phone?
왜 전화를 받지 않았나요?
I left it at the bakery.
빵집에 두고 왔습니다.
When I went back, they were already closed.
다시 가보니 이미 문이 닫혀 있었습니다.
You didn't have to get this.
당신은 이것을 얻을 필요가 없었습니다.
And from now on, tell me to get these.
그리고 이제부터 이거 가져오라고 해주세요.
No.
아니요.
I'm much better than you at picking out ingredients.
재료 고르는 건 내가 너보다 훨씬 잘해 .
Goodness, I'm glad I made the soup earlier.
맙소사, 수프를 일찍 만들어서 다행이에요.
Honey, you should also celebrate Ha-young's birthday with us.
여보, 하영이 생일 도 우리와 함께 축하해주세요 .
The sky is blue, and cherry blossoms are in full blossom.
하늘은 파랗고, 벚꽃이 만개했습니다.
The weather continues to stay nice and makes us feel warm.
날씨가 계속해서 좋은 편 이어서 기분이 따뜻해졌습니다.
The temperature will rise tomorrow,
내일 기온이 올라갈 것입니다.
and it'll be a bit hotter in the south like early summer.
그리고 초여름처럼 남쪽은 조금 더 더울 것입니다 .
But the air is a bit drier.
하지만 공기가 좀 더 건조해요.
In Chungcheong and Gangwon…
충청과 강원에서???
-What's that? -The daily case report.
- 그게 뭐죠? - 일일 사례보고.
I said we won't return to the office after visiting the prison,
교도소 방문 후에 는 사무실로 돌아오지 않겠다고 했는데 ,
and Woo-ju gave these to me.
우주가 이걸 나한테 줬어요.
Where did we find a such treasure like that kid?
그 아이 같은 보물은 어디서 찾았나요 ?
I still have good luck with people.
나는 아직도 사람들과 행운을 누리고 있습니다.
Am I included in that luck?
나도 그 행운에 포함되는 걸까?
Why? Do you think you aren't?
왜? 당신은 그렇지 않다고 생각하시나요?
You're worried over nothing.
당신은 아무 것도 걱정하지 않습니다.
-Nothing, right? -No.
-아무것도 아니죠? -아니요.
I'm not sure if that's good, or if finding something is good.
그게 좋은 것인지, 뭔가를 찾는 것이 좋은 것인지 잘 모르겠습니다 .
I wouldn't feel so frustrated only if we could figure out
우리가 그걸 알아낼 수만 있다면 그렇게 좌절감을 느끼지 않을 텐데
if he stopped or changed his MO.
그가 MO를 중단하거나 변경한 경우.
"Mugging in a residential area,
"주거지역에서 강도질을 하고,
stabbed in the left side, serious injury inflicted by the stab…"
왼쪽 옆구리 찔림, 찔림으로 심각한 부상???"
"Camping knife"?
"캠핑 나이프"?
-Camping knife? -Yes.
-캠핑칼? -예.
Why?
왜?
May I see that again?
다시 볼 수 있을까요?
-Which one? Sinheung 4-dong? -Yes.
-어느 것? 신흥4동? -예.
It's just an assault case.
바로 폭행사건입니다.
-May I see it? -Which one?
-제가 봐도 될까요? -어느 것?
"April 15, 3:30 a.m. A residential area, in public.
"4월 15일 오전 3시 30분, 주거 지역, 공공 장소.
Victim, female.
피해자, 여성.
Serious injury inflicted
심각한 부상을 입음
by a stab on the left side."
왼쪽을 찔러서."
-"Weapon was a camping knife." -Camping knife.
-"무기는 캠핑용 칼이었습니다." -캠핑칼.
Camping knife.
캠핑칼.
ATTACKED WITH A CAMPING KNIFE
캠핑용 칼로 공격당함
Could you please make a call to Woo-ju?
우주에게 전화 좀 걸어 주시겠어요?
Sure. One second.
확신하는. 일초.
Hey, Woo-ju.
안녕, 우주.
Can you look up "camping knife" and find some reports?
"캠핑 나이프"를 검색해 보고서를 찾아볼 수 있나요?
-Camping knife? -Yes, this year.
-캠핑칼? -예, 올해입니다.
I remember reading it.
나는 그것을 읽었던 것을 기억합니다.
One second.
일초.
You should begin with Dongjak Police Station.
동작경찰서 부터 시작해야 합니다 .
2004 DAILY CASE REPORT
2004년 일일 사례 보고서
CAMPING KNIFE
캠핑나이프
-Two cases popped up. -Two cases?
- 두 가지 경우가 나타났습니다. - 사건이 두 개요?
Yes. In Sinheung 5-dong and Sinheung 2-dong.
예. 신흥5동 과 신흥2동에 있습니다.
Both cases are from February this year.
두 사건 모두 올해 2월의 사건이다.
Tell me about the victims.
피해자들에 대해 말해주세요.
Both of them were women in their twenties.
두 사람 모두 20대 여성이었다.
And they have serious injuries.
그리고 그들은 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Both were categorized as assaults.
둘 다 폭행으로 분류됐다.
Print the case reports.
사례 보고서를 인쇄합니다.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Did you look into it?
조사해 보셨나요?
The cases in Guo-dong and Borim-dong took place in January and February.
궈동과 보림동에서는 1월과 2월에 사건이 발생했다.
Captain Yoon.
윤 선장.
Do you think it's the same guy?
같은 사람인 것 같은데?
Both victims had serious injuries.
두 피해자 모두 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
They were reported as assault cases.
이들은 폭행 사건으로 신고됐다.
Neither of the victims can remember his face?
피해자 중 누구도 그의 얼굴을 기억하지 못하는 걸까요?
They remember seeing him running away from the back.
그들은 그가 뒤에서 도망치는 모습을 기억합니다.
Both victims said that he was short and had a small build.
두 피해자 모두 키가 작고 체구가 작았 다고 말했습니다 .
But it might be a bit of a leap
하지만 약간의 도약일 수도 있습니다.
to say that they were attacked by the same guy.
같은 사람에게 공격을 받았다고 합니다 .
But the wealthy senior citizen murders happened in different districts.
하지만 부유한 노인 살인 사건은 여러 지역에서 일어났다.
But even if we assume that his MO changed,
하지만 그의 MO가 바뀌었다고 가정하더라도,
it's still confusing because the victims didn't die.
피해자들이 죽지 않았기 때문에 여전히 혼란스럽습니다 .
Both victims were
두 피해자는 모두
stabbed in the abdomen by a camping knife.
캠핑용 칼로 복부를 찔렀다.
The same weapon and location of the stab wounds.
무기 와 자상 위치가 동일합니다.
Based on this, we can assume that the culprit is the same person.
이를 토대로 범인이 동일인임을 추정할 수 있다.
But I'm not sure
하지만 잘 모르겠어요
if it's enough to report this as criminal intelligence.
이걸 범죄정보로 신고해도 충분하다면 .
This part bothers me the most.
이 부분이 가장 마음에 걸립니다.
A suspect who is 170cm with a small build.
170cm의 작은 체격을 지닌 피의자.
It's similar to the guy we're looking for.
우리가 찾고 있는 사람과 비슷해요.
This is from Geumcheon Police Station?
금천경찰서에서요?
Yes. The detective in charge is my friend.
예. 담당 형사는 내 친구예요.
And we recently had a drink.
그리고 우리는 최근에 술을 마셨습니다.
When he told me about this, it felt fishy. So we looked into it.
그가 나에게 이것에 대해 말했을 때, 그것은 수상한 느낌이었습니다. 그래서 우리는 그것을 조사했습니다.
What about this?
이건 어때?
At our last meeting, Inspector Song mentioned the possibility
지난 회의에서 송 경감은 가능성을 언급했다.
that he might change his MO.
그가 자신의 MO를 변경할 수도 있다는 것입니다.
I remembered what he said that day.
그날 그가 했던 말이 생각났다.
So we kept an eye out to see if there were any cases
그래서 우리는 어떤 사례가 있는지 살펴보았습니다.
following a pattern.
패턴을 따른다.
So these cases
그래서 이런 경우는
could have been executed by him?
그 사람에 의해 처형될 수도 있었나요?
That's what you mean?
그게 무슨 말이에요?
Whether it's true or not, it still bothers me.
그것이 사실이든 아니든 그것은 여전히 ​​나를 괴롭힌다.
But this isn't a homicide.
하지만 이건 살인이 아니다.
It's not enough to take over the cases.
사건을 인수하는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
They are just two assault cases.
그들은 단지 두 건의 폭행 사건입니다.
Let us investigate this ourselves.
이에 대해서는 직접 조사해보자.
Goodness. It's all because of this jerk.
선량. 이게 다 이 놈 때문이에요.
I'm starting to see everything as serial murder.
나는 모든 것을 연쇄 살인으로 보기 시작했습니다 .
All cases bring him to my mind.
모든 사건이 그를 떠올리게 한다.
Same here.
여기도 마찬가지입니다.
But these cases don't seem to suit his style.
하지만 이런 경우는 그의 스타일에는 맞지 않는 것 같다.
Whether it's him or not, if we are suspicious,
그 사람이든 아니든 의심이 든다면
we must investigate.
우리는 조사해야 합니다.
Even if we waste time, that's better than losing him
시간을 낭비하더라도 그 사람을 잃는 것보다는 낫지
because we didn't try.
왜냐하면 우리는 시도하지 않았기 때문입니다.
Woo-ju, you got the reports?
우주야, 보고서 받았어?
Are they important cases?
중요한 사건인가요?
-We're not sure yet. -Is it him?
-아직 확실하지 않습니다. -그 사람인가요?
There's a small possibility if he changed his MO.
MO를 바꾸면 가능성은 거의 없습니다 .
We'll be back. Let's go.
우리는 돌아올거야. 갑시다.
We'll be back.
우리는 돌아올거야.
The victim is in the hospital now.
피해자는 현재 병원에 입원 중이다.
She needs to rest.
그녀는 휴식이 필요합니다.
So you can't meet her.
그래서 당신은 그녀를 만날 수 없습니다.
-This is her statement. -Okay.
-그녀의 진술입니다. -좋아요.
He kept following her,
그는 계속해서 그녀를 따라다녔고,
so she threw him her purse.
그래서 그녀는 그에게 지갑을 던졌습니다.
But he wasn't interested.
그러나 그는 관심이 없었습니다.
How did you confirm it was a camping knife?
캠핑용 칼인지 어떻게 확인하셨나요 ?
Given the size of the stab wound, we knew it wasn't a kitchen knife.
찔린 상처의 크기로 보아 그것이 부엌칼이 아니라는 것을 알았습니다.
The victim also said that the knife was small.
피해자는 칼도 작았다고 말했다.
The size was about half of our palm.
크기는 우리 손바닥의 절반 정도였어요.
I showed her a few photos.
나는 그녀에게 사진 몇 장을 보여주었다.
And she chose camping knives.
그리고 그녀는 캠핑용 칼을 선택했습니다.
-Was there an eyewitness? -Yes.
-목격자가 있었나요? -예.
He heard screams, so he opened the window and yelled.
그는 비명소리를 듣고 창문을 열고 소리쳤다.
Then the culprit ran away.
그러자 범인은 도망갔습니다.
He was short, skinny, balding, and wearing a shabby tracksuit.
그는 키가 작고, 말랐으며, 대머리였고, 초라한 운동복을 입고 있었습니다.
Can we meet with him?
그 사람을 만날 수 있을까요?
Sure.
확신하는.
And what about the other two cases?
그리고 나머지 두 가지 경우는 어떻습니까?
The other two cases?
나머지 두 사건은요?
Two cases with a similar MO took place in February.
지난 2월에는 유사한 MO를 가진 두 건의 사례가 발생했습니다.
Take a look here.
여기를 보세요.
-Sinheung 5-dong. -Okay.
-신흥5동. -좋아요.
Sinheung 2-dong.
신흥2동.
You need to ask the team in charge. I don't know about this.
담당팀에 문의하셔야 합니다. 나는 이것에 대해 모른다.
He's in charge. Detective Kim, come here.
그는 책임자입니다. 김 형사님, 이리 오세요.
He followed her in front of her home.
그는 그녀의 집 앞에서 그녀를 따라갔습니다.
He stabbed her when she had her key in the hole.
그녀가 구멍에 열쇠를 꽂고 있을 때 그는 그녀를 찔렀습니다.
He sounded like a total nutcase.
그는 완전히 미친 사람처럼 들렸습니다.
Did he try to steal her wallet?
그가 지갑을 훔치려고 했나?
After stabbing her, he left without touching her bag.
그는 그녀를 찌른 뒤 가방에 손도 대지 않은 채 떠났다.
So the victim was about to go in.
그래서 피해자가 들어가려고 했어요.
And the bastard jumped on her.
그리고 그 개자식은 그녀에게 뛰어 올랐습니다.
Then he turned her around.
그런 다음 그는 그녀를 돌아섰습니다.
And he started stabbing.
그리고 그는 찌르기 시작했습니다.
She couldn't remember his face as she was shocked.
그녀는 충격을 받아 그의 얼굴을 기억하지 못했다 .
She said he was short. Right.
그녀는 그가 키가 작다고 말했습니다. 오른쪽.
He was about 170cm tall.
키는 170cm쯤 됐어요.
Not having security cameras in a blind spot like this
이렇게 사각지대에 감시카메라가 없으면
is always a problem.
항상 문제입니다.
But we have more than last year.
하지만 우리는 작년보다 더 많은 것을 가지고 있습니다.
This is an improvement.
이는 개선된 사항입니다.
Right. That's good.
오른쪽. 좋아요.
-But we still need more. -Right.
-하지만 아직은 더 필요해요. -오른쪽.
-Is that the house? -Yes. The second floor.
- 저게 집이에요? -예. 2층.
That's where I screamed.
내가 비명을 질렀던 곳이 바로 그 곳이었다.
Where was the culprit?
범인은 어디에 있었나요?
Over there. Under the streetlamp.
저기요. 가로등 아래.
Something seemed off, so I was watching them.
뭔가 이상한 것 같아서 지켜보고 있었어요.
All of a sudden, the woman started screaming.
갑자기 여자가 비명을 지르기 시작했다.
So I screamed, "Hey! What are you doing?"
그래서 나는 “야! 뭐하는 거야?”라고 소리쳤습니다.
When I screamed,
내가 비명을 질렀을 때
he ran away. And he was really fast.
그는 도망쳤어요. 그리고 그는 정말 빨랐습니다.
You also said that he was short.
키가 작다고도 하셨어요.
He was short.
그는 키가 작았습니다.
He was losing hair. He had a bald spot.
그는 머리카락을 잃고있었습니다. 그에게는 대머리가 있었습니다.
Didn't he wear hiking shoes?
그 사람 등산화를 신지 않았나요?
I'm not sure about that.
나는 그것에 대해 확실하지 않다.
Right. You were pretty far.
오른쪽. 꽤 멀리 계셨습니다.
What do you mean by he was fast?
그 사람이 빨랐다는 게 무슨 말이야?
The light was bright, so I could see him running away.
빛이 밝아서 그가 도망가는 모습이 보였습니다.
Enough for you to see he was a fast runner?
그가 빠른 주자라는 것을 알 수 있을 만큼 충분합니까 ?
Yes. I was surprised by how fast he was.
예. 나는 그가 얼마나 빠른지 놀랐다.
The victim suspected it could've been an act of retaliation.
피해자는 보복행위일 수도 있다고 의심했다.
So we assumed it could've been an acquaintance.
그래서 우리는 그것이 지인일 수도 있다고 가정했습니다.
We started questioning her friends.
우리는 그녀의 친구들에게 질문하기 시작했습니다.
You didn't find any fingerprints or evidence for either case?
두 사건 모두 지문이나 증거를 찾지 못하셨나요 ?
Right. He followed her to her house like he was determined to attack her.
오른쪽. 그는 그녀를 공격하겠다고 결심한 것처럼 그녀를 따라 그녀의 집으로 갔다 .
She wasn't sure if he was following her.
그녀는 그가 그녀를 따르고 있는지 확신하지 못했습니다.
But he came into the building too.
그런데 그 사람도 건물 안으로 들어왔어요.
And he took something out of his jacket
그리고 그는 재킷에서 뭔가를 꺼냈습니다
and stabbed her right away.
그리고 곧바로 그녀를 찔렀다.
This case took place in Guo-dong.
이번 사건은 궈동에서 일어났습니다.
But it's the same MO with Borim-dong.
그런데 보림동도 마찬가지다.
The location changed, but still no evidence.
위치가 바뀌었지만 여전히 증거는 없습니다.
On top of that, it rained that day.
게다가 그날은 비가 내렸습니다.
A camping knife, a stab wound to the abdomen,
캠핑용 칼, 복부에 찔린 상처,
and no valuables or money were taken.
귀중품이나 돈은 가져 가지 않았습니다.
She didn't know she was being followed because of the rain.
그녀는 비 때문에 미행 을 당하고 있는 줄도 몰랐습니다 .
The victim was on the ground.
피해자는 현장에 있었습니다.
When he saw a car coming,
그는 차가 오는 것을 보고
he was surprised and ran away.
그는 놀라서 도망갔다.
The descriptions are similar.
설명은 비슷합니다.
-But no luck yet? -He was short.
-근데 아직 운이 없나요? -그는 키가 작았어요.
And when she was on the ground, she saw his feet.
그리고 그녀가 땅에 있을 때, 그녀는 그의 발을 보았습니다.
He was wearing sneakers.
그는 운동화를 신고 있었습니다.
Not hiking shoes?
등산화 아님?
She said he wore sneakers.
운동화를 신었다고 하더군요.
Sneakers.
운동화.
The fact that he didn't take money or valuables bothers me the most.
그 사람이 돈이나 귀중품을 가져가지 않았다는 사실이 가장 마음에 걸립니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
He committed crimes in January and February.
그는 1월과 2월에 범죄를 저질렀다 .
It's April, but he hasn't committed any crimes since.
4월인데 그 이후로 그는 어떤 범죄도 저지르지 않았습니다.
Is this the cooling-off period the Analysis Team mentioned?
이게 분석팀이 언급한 냉각기간인가요 ?
Let's check the scene first.
먼저 현장을 확인해보겠습니다.
Is this the place?
이 곳인가요?
Yes, it is.
예, 그렇습니다.
-This is way too bright. -I know, right?
-너무 밝습니다. - 나도 알아, 그렇지?
That's odd.
그거 이상 하네.
Three people with serious stab wounds from a camping knife after being attacked.
캠핑용 칼에 공격을 받아 심각한 자상을 입은 세 사람 .
All of them took place late at dawn.
모두 늦은 새벽에 일어났습니다.
All of the victims were young women.
피해자는 모두 젊은 여성이었다.
The only difference is that one was in an alley.
유일한 차이점은 골목에 있다는 것입니다.
The other two were in front of houses.
나머지 두 명은 집 앞에 있었다.
They were attacked in different locations, but having three cases with the same MO
서로 다른 위치에서 공격을 받았지만 동일한 MO로 3건의 사례가 발생했습니다.
implies that there might be more cases.
더 많은 경우가 발생할 수 있음을 의미합니다.
And all of the victims were stabbed in their stomachs.
그리고 피해자들은 모두 배를 찔렀습니다.
Do you think it's him?
그 사람인 것 같아?
I doubt it.
나는 그것을 의심한다.
The weapon, MO, and time don't match at all.
무기, MO, 시간이 전혀 일치하지 않습니다.
But they seem to have a similar build.
하지만 비슷한 구조를 가지고 있는 것 같습니다.
Right. That's why we can't be certain.
오른쪽. 그렇기 때문에 우리는 확신할 수 없습니다.
But he was a fast runner.
그러나 그는 빠른 주자였습니다.
If he was visibly fast, I don't think he could've done that in hiking boots.
만약 그가 눈에 띄게 빠르다면 등산화를 신고 그렇게 할 수 없었을 것입니다.
Right. You can't run fast in hiking boots.
오른쪽. 등산화를 신은 채 빨리 달릴 수는 없습니다.
There's a photo of him from behind, and we know he wore hiking boots.
그의 뒤에서 찍은 사진이 있는데, 우리는 그가 등산화를 신었다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
He won't wear them.
그는 그것을 입지 않을 것입니다.
But the guy we're looking for
그런데 우리가 찾고 있는 그 사람이
killed victims with a blunt weapon without giving them a chance to resist.
저항할 틈도 주지 않고 둔기로 피해자를 살해했다 .
Even if he changed his MO,
MO를 바꾸더라도,
I don't think he would use such a small knife.
내 생각엔 그 사람이 그렇게 작은 칼을 사용할 것 같지 않아요 .
Let's say that it is him.
그 사람이라고 가정 해 봅시다.
All of these assault cases would be attempted murder cases.
이런 폭행 사건은 모두 살인미수 사건이다.
It won't be enough for him.
그에게는 충분하지 않을 것입니다.
So he wouldn't have used the same weapon three times.
그러므로 그는 같은 무기를 세 번 사용하지 않았을 것입니다 .
He repeated his crimes.
그는 자신의 범죄를 반복했습니다.
That means he didn't check if the victim was dead, right?
피해자가 죽었는지 확인하지 않았다는 뜻이겠죠 ?
But that doesn't change anything.
그러나 그것은 아무것도 바꾸지 않습니다.
He barely left any evidence after breaking into the houses.
그는 집에 침입한 후 증거를 거의 남기지 않았습니다 .
Following his victims?
피해자를 추적한다고?
There could've been witnesses. He wouldn't take risks like that
목격자가 있었을 수도 있어요. 그 사람은 그런 위험을 감수하지 않을 거야
because he's super careful.
왜냐면 그 사람은 정말 조심스럽거든요.
What if it's not him?
그 사람이 아니면 어쩌지?
Since all the victims were injured,
피해자들이 모두 부상을 입었기 때문에
we're not looking for a murderer, but a violent man who robs people.
우리가 찾고 있는 것은 살인자 가 아니라 사람의 물건을 강탈하는 폭력적인 사람입니다.
No. He wasn't interested in valuables. He's not a robber.
아뇨. 그는 귀중품에는 관심이 없었습니다. 그는 강도가 아닙니다.
What if it's what we speculated?
만약 그것이 우리가 추측한 대로라면 어떨까요?
What if the victims were only injured…
피해자만 부상당했다면???
because he failed to finish the job?
그 사람이 일을 끝내지 못했기 때문에?
Then…
그 다음에???
we have two serial killers in this country.
이 나라에는 두 명의 연쇄 살인범이 있습니다 .
GIRLS IN THEIR TWENTIES
20대 소녀
This one didn't die either?
이 사람도 죽지 않았나요?
The same weapons were used.
동일한 무기가 사용되었습니다.
"A camping knife"?
"캠핑용 칼"?
Look, these three locations aren't far from one another.
보세요, 이 세 곳은 서로 멀지 않습니다.
The weapon, where the victims were attacked,
피해자들이 공격받았던 무기는 ,
and even the time. These cases have a lot in common.
그리고 심지어 시간. 이 사건들은 공통점이 많습니다.
"Seriously injured…"
"심각하게 부상당한???"
Why?
왜?
Is it because they aren't murders?
살인이 아니기 때문일까요?
Is there something else?
다른 것이 있나요?
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
Captain Yoon, come here for a moment.
윤 대위님, 잠시 이리로 오세요.
Guo-dong and Borim-dong.
궈동과 보림동.
These cases took place in January and February of this year.
이번 사건은 올해 1월과 2월에 발생했다 .
We believe these were done by the culprit of the serial murders.
우리는 이것이 연쇄 살인범의 소행이라고 믿습니다 .
We're investigating at the moment.
현재 조사 중입니다.
It's not the same guy.
같은 사람이 아닙니다.
What?
무엇?
It's a different guy.
다른 사람이에요.
His build is similar.
그의 빌드는 비슷합니다.
Other than that, they have nothing else in common.
그 외에는 공통점이 없습니다.
From the MO to the weapons, everything's different.
MO부터 무기까지 모든 것이 다릅니다.
Didn't you say the MO could change?
MO가 바뀔 수 있다고 하지 않았나요?
Yes, it could change.
예, 바뀔 수 있습니다.
But he already got a taste of using blunt weapons.
하지만 그는 이미 둔기 사용의 맛을 보았습니다 .
He won't change his weapon to something smaller.
그는 무기를 더 작은 것으로 바꾸지 않을 것입니다 .
Then there's less chance this guy is a serial killer.
그러면 이 사람이 연쇄살인범일 확률은 낮아집니다 .
These victims didn't die.
이 피해자들은 죽지 않았습니다.
Thankfully, they're alive.
다행히 그들은 살아있습니다.
But it could actually make the culprit even more violent.
하지만 실제로는 범인을 더욱 폭력적으로 만들 수도 있습니다.
We must catch him before there's another victim.
또 다른 피해자가 생기기 전에 그를 잡아야 합니다 .
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
This serial killer is already giving us a huge headache.
이 연쇄 살인범은 이미 우리에게 큰 골칫거리를 안겨주고 있습니다.
How will we track down a murder that hasn't even happened yet?
아직 일어나지도 않은 살인 사건을 어떻게 추적할 것인가 ?
Let's draw a facial composite.
얼굴 합성을 그려 봅시다.
Yes, let's start with a facial composite.
예, 얼굴 합성부터 시작해 보겠습니다.
All the victims are alive.
피해자들은 모두 살아있습니다.
We have a witness too.
우리에게도 증인이 있습니다.
The victims are traumatized and don't remember his face.
피해자들은 충격에 휩싸여 얼굴도 기억나지 않는다.
Let's try forensic hypnosis.
법의학 최면을 시도해 봅시다.
He has a slim face.
그는 날씬한 얼굴을 가지고 있습니다.
USE OF HYPNOSIS IN THE INVESTIGATIVE PROCESS TO FIND CLUES
단서를 찾기 위한 조사 과정 에서 최면술의 사용
He has small, slanted eyes.
그는 작고 비스듬한 눈을 가지고 있습니다.
And…
그리고???
Right.
오른쪽.
He was somewhat bald.
그는 다소 대머리였습니다.
Where? The forehead?
어디? 이마?
Yes.
예.
NATIONAL FORENSICS SERVICE
국립과학수사서비스
As you know, the killer isn't after money.
아시다시피 범인은 돈을 노리는 게 아닙니다.
FACIAL COMPOSITE RESULT
얼굴 복합 결과
If it's not about money or grudges,
돈이나 원한에 관한 것이 아니라면
there can be only one purpose.
목적은 단 하나뿐입니다.
Killing.
살인.
Yes, he looked somewhat like this.
네, 그 사람은 좀 이렇게 생겼어요.
He was skinny, so he had a slim face like this.
마른 체형 이라 얼굴이 이렇게 날씬했어요.
This is pretty accurate.
이것은 꽤 정확합니다.
-Thank you. -No problem.
-감사합니다. -괜찮아요.
Let's go.
갑시다.
You're here.
너 여기 있네.
Take a look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
We had the witness verify the accuracy of this composite.
우리는 목격자에게 이 합성물의 정확성을 확인하도록 했습니다.
Looks good, right?
괜찮아 보이는데요?
So this scum may be the one who killed the senior citizens.
그러니까 이 쓰레기가 노인들을 죽인 게 아닐까 .
It's not the same guy.
같은 사람이 아닙니다.
No.
아니요.
We'll continue to investigate based on the possibility of him
가능성을 토대로 계속 조사해보겠습니다
being the same guy.
같은 사람이니까.
Whether it's the same guy or not,
같은 사람인지 아닌지,
we're investigating the same case, aren't we?
우리도 같은 사건을 조사하고 있지 않나요?
-Yes, we are. -Very well.
-네, 우리는. -아주 잘.
-Let's go through it again. -Okay.
- 다시 한번 살펴보겠습니다. -좋아요.
It took place late at night
늦은 밤에 일어났어요
under a brightly lit streetlamp.
환하게 켜진 가로등 아래.
The Borim-dong case also took place under a streetlamp.
보림동 사건 도 가로등 밑에서 벌어졌다.
Normally, suspects look for dark spots to hide.
일반적으로 용의자는 숨을 만한 어두운 점을 찾습니다 .
And the victims were attacked from the front, not from behind.
그리고 피해자들은 뒤에서가 아닌 앞에서 공격을 받았다.
Did he reveal his face on purpose?
일부러 얼굴을 공개한 걸까요?
-Hold on. Watch this. -Okay.
-기다리다. 이것을보세요. -좋아요.
The victim
피해자
was walking this way.
이쪽으로 걷고 있었어요.
She suddenly felt that someone was following her.
그녀는 갑자기 누군가가 자신을 따라오고 있다는 느낌을 받았습니다.
She threw her purse, so he'd take it and leave.
그녀는 지갑을 던졌고 그는 그것을 가지고 떠날 것입니다.
But he didn't care about the purse and kept following her,
하지만 그는 지갑에는 개의치 않고 계속해서 그녀를 따라다녔고,
so she started walking faster, terrified.
그래서 그녀는 겁에 질려 더 빨리 걷기 시작했습니다.
The culprit must've continued to follow her.
범인은 계속 그녀를 따라다녔나 보다.
Then he suddenly
그러다 갑자기 그 사람이
swung his knife at her.
그녀에게 칼을 휘둘렀다.
-Hold on. -He made her turn around on purpose.
-기다리다. -그는 일부러 그녀를 돌아보게 만들었어요.
But it could've happened the moment she happened to turn around.
하지만 그녀가 우연히 돌아선 순간에 그런 일이 일어났을 수도 있다 .
One commonality of these cases is that
이들 사례의 공통점 중 하나는
their abdomen was stabbed.
복부가 찔 렸습니다.
They were stabbed from the front.
그들은 정면에서 칼에 찔렸습니다.
They took place in the southwestern part.
그들은 남서부 지역에서 일어났습니다.
Maybe he lives in the area.
어쩌면 그 사람이 그 지역에 살고 있을지도 몰라요.
Why does the Special Crime Squad think these cases
특수수사대는 왜 이런 사건을 생각하는가 ?
were committed by the culprit who killed the rich senior citizens?
부자 노인들을 죽인 범인이 저질렀다고 ?
That scum targeted luxurious houses
그 쓰레기는 고급 주택을 표적으로 삼았습니다.
in Gangnam and Gangbuk.
강남과 강북에서.
But as you can see on this map,
하지만 이 지도에서 볼 수 있듯이
this isn't a rich neighborhood.
이곳은 부유한 동네가 아닙니다.
Let's go through everything again.
모든 것을 다시 살펴 보겠습니다.
Our theory is that
우리의 이론은
he attacked the victims to kill them.
그는 피해자들을 죽이려고 공격했습니다.
And these attacks took place
그리고 이러한 공격이 일어났습니다.
five times in southwestern Seoul.
서울 남서부에서 다섯 번.
That could mean he didn't know that the victims didn't die.
피해자가 죽지 않았다는 사실을 몰랐다는 뜻일 수도 있다 .
Will his MO change when he finds out they didn't die?
그들이 죽지 않았다는 사실을 알게 되면 그의 MO가 바뀔까요 ?
It's highly likely.
가능성이 높습니다.
If he didn't know they didn't die,
몰랐다면 그들은 죽지 않았을 것이다.
and if that was why he kept using the same MO,
그래서 계속 같은 MO를 사용했다면,
these "attacks" could turn into murders once he finds out.
이러한 "공격"은 일단 그가 알게 되면 살인으로 바뀔 수 있습니다.
In fact, that is what I'm most worried about.
사실 그게 가장 걱정이에요.
Then how would he find out?
그러면 그 사람은 어떻게 알 수 있겠습니까?
Through the news or the newspapers, probably.
아마도 뉴스 나 신문을 통해서일 겁니다.
Or he could visit the scenes again.
아니면 현장을 다시 방문할 수도 있습니다.
You said it rained when the attack took place.
공격이 일어났을 때 비가 왔다고 하더군요 .
Yes.
예.
You can't see clearly when it's raining, which makes it easier
비가 오면 잘 보이지 않아서 더 쉽습니다.
to commit crimes.
범죄를 저지르는 것.
On top of choosing a brightly lit spot,
조명이 밝은 곳을 선택하는 것 외에도
he purposely revealed his face. Why?
일부러 얼굴을 공개했다. 왜?
This wasn't about a personal grudge, so why did he reveal his face?
개인적인 원한이 아닌데 왜 얼굴을 공개한 걸까요?
Why? Why did he do that?
왜? 왜 그랬나요?
I really don't get it.
정말 이해가 안 돼요.
What time did the incident take place?
사건이 발생한 시간은 언제입니까?
Around 9 p.m.
오후 9시쯤
-Let's go back to the scene in Borim-dong. -Yes, ma'am.
- 다시 보림동 현장으로 돌아가 보자. -네 부인.
So we'll check this area every day from now on, right?
그럼 앞으로는 이 부분을 매일 확인하도록 하지요 ?
Yes.
예.
Do you really think the culprit will return to the scene?
정말 범인이 현장에 돌아올 것이라고 생각하시나요 ?
First, we have to put ourselves in his shoes.
먼저 우리는 그의 입장에서 생각해야 합니다 .
Why did he choose these areas?
그가 이 지역을 선택한 이유는 무엇입니까?
Did he look for easy spots
쉬운 곳을 찾았나요
where he can attack and run?
어디에서 공격하고 달릴 수 있나요?
Or is he familiar with this area?
아니면 이 분야에 대해 잘 알고 있나요?
Gosh, this feels like a waste of time.
맙소사, 이건 시간낭비인 것 같아.
I feel like we're on a stakeout
우리가 측량 중인 것 같아
for something that hasn't happened yet.
아직 일어나지 않은 일 때문에.
No, we're not. We're trying to track down
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다. 우리는 추적을 시도하고 있습니다
a serial killer
연쇄 살인범
who has already committed murders.
이미 살인을 저지른 사람.
It is the same case,
같은 경우인데,
but remember that we're looking at it from a different perspective,
하지만 우리는 이 문제를 다른 관점에서 보고 있다는 점을 기억하세요 .
on the premise that it's the same guy.
같은 사람이라는 전제 하에.
PUREUMAE PARK, DONGJAK-GU
동작구 푸른매공원
This early morning at Seoul Pureumae Park,
오늘 이른 아침, 서울 푸른매공원
a woman in her twenties was found stabbed to death.
20대 여성이 칼에 찔려 숨진 채 발견됐다.
The victim had been stabbed multiple times
피해자는 여러 차례 칼에 찔렸습니다
and had already lost a lot of blood when she was found.
발견 당시 이미 많은 피를 흘린 상태였습니다 .
People were heartbroken to hear she passed away in the ambulance
그녀가 구급차에서 사망했다는 소식을 듣고 사람들은 가슴이 아팠습니다
on the way to the hospital.
병원으로 가는 길
The crime occurred at a blind spot where there were no security cameras.
범죄는 보안카메라도 없는 사각지대에서 발생했다.
It's been a struggle to find traces of the culprit due to a lack of witnesses.
증인이 부족해 범인의 흔적을 찾는 데 어려움을 겪었습니다 .
The importance of having safety measures in parks
공원 안전 조치 의 중요성
has been raised.
올랐습니다.
Seoul City has announced that they will inspect the parks' streetlamps
서울시는 공원의 가로등을 점검하겠다고 발표했습니다
and install more security cameras to remove blind spots.
사각지대를 제거하기 위해 더 많은 보안 카메라를 설치합니다 .
MAP OF SEOUL
서울 지도
The Pureumae Case also occurred in the southwestern district.
푸어매 사건은 서남부 지역에서도 발생했다.
This happened at a park though, not a residential street.
주택가가 아닌 공원 에서 일어난 일입니다 .
And the weapon wasn't a camping knife but a kitchen knife.
그리고 그 무기는 캠핑용 칼이 아닌 부엌용 칼이었습니다.
You're seeing this as the same guy when it's this different?
이렇게 다른데 이 사람을 같은 사람으로 보는 건가요 ?
Or is it a third suspect?
아니면 세 번째 용의자인가?
Come on, just hear him out.
어서, 그의 말을 들어보세요.
Carry on.
계속하세요.
A woman in her twenties was stabbed in the abdomen late at night.
20대 여성이 늦은 밤 복부를 찔렸습니다.
The time of the crime and area of attack match the other victims.
범행시간과 공격지역은 다른 피해자들과 일치한다.
Although it's a park,
공원임에도 불구하고
it's a shortcut to the residential area
주거지역으로 가는 지름길이에요
so residents of this neighborhood
그래서 이 동네 주민들은
often use this route.
이 길을 자주 이용하세요.
Why does that matter?
그게 왜 중요해요?
I'm saying, it has to be considered a residential alley.
주거용 골목 이라고 봐야죠 .
We have a description of the suspect too.
용의자에 대한 설명도 있어요.
Wait, there was a witness?
잠깐, 목격자가 있었다고요?
No.
아니요.
The victim gave testimony while being transported by ambulance.
피해자는 구급차에 실려 이송되는 동안 증언을 했다.
I guess…
그런거 같은데???
she was alive up until then.
그녀는 그때까지 살아 있었습니다.
It was a man in his thirties, about 170cm in height
키 170cm 정도의 30대 남성이었습니다.
with little hair,
작은 머리카락으로,
dressed in dark workout clothes.
어두운 운동복을 입고 있다.
In a phone call with her boyfriend right after the incident, she said,
사건 직후 A씨는 남자친구와 통화에서 이렇게 말했다.
"A stranger followed me and stabbed me with a knife."
"낯선 사람이 따라오더니 칼로 찔렀어요."
The conversation ended with that.
대화는 그것으로 끝났다.
Just as we feared,
우리가 두려워했던 것처럼,
the culprit wasn't satisfied with his last crime.
범인은 그의 마지막 범죄에 만족하지 않았습니다.
We assumed he committed another crime with a larger and sharper weapon.
우리는 그가 더 크고 더 날카로운 무기로 또 다른 범죄를 저질렀다고 추측했습니다.
-I still disagree. -With what?
-아직도 동의하지 않습니다. -무엇으로?
I disagree with everything that the Analysis Team says.
나는 분석팀이 말하는 모든 것에 동의하지 않습니다.
Don't you think it's time we stop being swayed by them?
이제 우리가 그들에게 더 이상 휘둘리지 않을 때가 되지 않았나요 ?
-Damn it. -Gosh, that temper of his.
-젠장. -맙소사, 그 사람 성격이 그래요.
Just let him be.
그냥 그대로 두세요.
So then the Analysis Team thinks
그러면 분석팀은 생각합니다.
that the culprit of the Southwest Case
사우스웨스트 사건의 범인
and this one is the same guy, right?
그리고 이 사람도 같은 사람이죠?
Yes. If you take a look at the pictures from the scene,
예. 현장 사진을 보시면 ,
it's neither sexual assault nor mugging.
성폭행도 아니고 강도도 아니다.
It's a different guy from the serial murders of the rich elderly then?
그렇다면 부자노인 연쇄살인과는 다른 놈인가 ?
Yes.
예.
I don't want to say this,
나는 이런 말을 하고 싶지 않다.
but we have to catch
하지만 우리는 잡아야 해
two serial killers.
두 명의 연쇄 살인범.
Don't blow this matter up hastily.
이 문제를 성급하게 폭로하지 마십시오.
If we announce
우리가 발표하면
there are two serial killers without clear evidence,
뚜렷한 증거가 없는 연쇄살인범이 두 명 있는데 ,
the level of anxiety the public feel will only multiply.
대중이 느끼는 불안의 수준은 더욱 커질 것입니다.
Their trust in the police will also waver.
경찰에 대한 신뢰도 흔들릴 것이다.
Physical evidence found at the scene is not the only clue.
현장에서 발견된 물적 증거 만이 유일한 단서는 아니다.
There are bound to be traces in the time and place he resided that day.
그날 그가 살았던 시간과 장소에는 흔적이 남아있을 것이다 .
A trace that may seem trivial
사소해 보일 수도 있는 흔적
becomes an important clue.
중요한 단서가 됩니다.
We can't only look at the weapon, but we must expand the conditions
무기만 볼 수는 없지만 조건을 확장해야 합니다.
and look to see if there are any similar cases.
그리고 비슷한 사례가 있는지 살펴보세요 .
So?
그래서?
You want us to request cooperation from the 31 police stations in Seoul?
서울 31개 경찰서에 협조를 요청하라는 건가요 ?
I think if we can, we must do it.
가능하다면 반드시 해야 한다고 생각합니다.
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1, TEAM 1
특수범죄수사대 1, 1팀
-Is he serious? -Seriously?
-그 사람 진심이에요? -진지하게?
We have so much to do.
우리는 할 일이 너무 많습니다.
-Gosh. -This is nonsense.
-맙소사. - 말도 안 되는 소리야.
The Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency and the Special Crime Squad
서울지방경찰청 및 특수수사대
held a meeting with 31 chiefs of police
경찰서장 31명과 간담회
to solve the serial attacks on women in southwest Seoul.
서울 남서부 여성에 대한 연쇄 공격을 해결하기 위해 .
They established an information room for crimes with no motives
무의미한 범죄를 신고하기 위한 정보실을 설치했습니다
and announced they'll be increasing cooperative investigations.
협력 조사를 늘릴 것이라고 발표했습니다 .
We are a personal bodyguard service.
저희는 개인 경호 서비스입니다.
A bodyguard just for myself--
나만을 위한 경호원--
Self-defense sprays.
호신용 스프레이
Now offering a huge discount.
지금 엄청난 할인 혜택을 제공하고 있습니다.
The reason is…
이유는???
With violent crimes targeting women happening consecutively
여성을 대상으로 한 강력범죄가 연달아 발생하면서
in the southwestern district of Seoul,
서울 남서부
the level of anxiety has jumped among the people.
사람들의 불안 수준이 급증했습니다 .
Within this year, there have been six cases of attacks in this area.
올해에만 이 지역에서 6건의 공격이 발생했습니다.
It's been revealed that one of these cases was a murder
이 사건 중 하나가 살인인 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
causing huge shock in the community.
커뮤니티에 큰 충격을 안겨줍니다.
We'll connect to Reporter Kim Ju-young.
김주영 기자에게 연결해드리겠습니다.
Past midnight on the 16th at Pureumae Park,
16일 자정이 넘은 푸른매공원
a murder occurred.
살인이 발생했습니다.
Pureumae Park is looking empty
푸르매공원은 텅 비어 보인다
due to no visitors coming by.
방문객이 없기 때문입니다.
One citizen expressed her anxiety by saying,
한 시민은 다음과 같이 불안을 표현했습니다 .
"I'm scared to walk alone, so I'm refraining from going out."
"혼자 걷기가 무서워서 외출을 자제하고 있습니다."
The police have increased the amount of questioning
경찰의 심문량이 늘어났습니다
and have been doing their best in trying to obtain evidence.
증거 확보에 최선을 다해 왔습니다 .
But they haven't made much progress.
그러나 그들은 많은 진전을 이루지 못했습니다.
LOOKING FOR WITNESSES 10 MILLION WON REWARD
증인을 찾는다 보상금 1000만원
Another late night for you.
당신을 위한 또 다른 늦은 밤.
You must be tired.
피곤하겠네요.
-Are you going to morning mass? -Yes.
-아침미사 가시나요? -예.
I'll drop you off.
내려드릴게요.
Gosh, it's fine. I go there every week anyway.
맙소사, 괜찮아요. 어쨌든 나는 매주 거기에 간다.
It's bright outside. Don't worry.
밖은 밝습니다. 괜찮아요.
No, I'll drop you off. Come on out.
아니요, 내려드릴게요. 나오세요.
My goodness. I told you, it's fine.
이럴 수가. 내가 말했잖아, 괜찮아.
Please think of your servant Michael
당신의 종 마이클을 생각해 주십시오.
whom you called away from this world.
당신이 이 세상에서 불러낸 사람.
He participated in the saint's death
그는 성자의 죽음에 참여했다
through baptism.
세례를 통해.
So please let him enjoy his resurrection too.
그러니 그 사람 도 부활을 즐기게 해주세요.
Those who are asleep with hopes…
희망을 품고 잠들어 있는 분들???
The devil has yet again disappeared without a trace.
악마가 또다시 흔적도 없이 사라졌습니다.
Please think of them
그들을 생각해 주세요
and let them meet your shining face.
그리고 그들이 당신의 빛나는 얼굴을 만나게 해주세요.
JULY 2004
2004년 7월
Why are they under construction every day?
왜 매일 공사가 진행되는 걸까요?
They're going to build a house soon.
그들은 곧 집을 지을 예정이다.
The noise is killing me.
소음이 나를 죽인다.
Police.
경찰.
SENIOR INSPECTOR KOOK YOUNG-SOO
국영수 경감
I'm a police officer.
저는 경찰관입니다.
Yes.
예.
"Spooky Thursdays."
"으스스한 목요일."
They've stopped night studies at girls' high schools.
그들은 여자 고등학교의 야간 학습을 중단했습니다.
I have nightmares every night because I'm worried
걱정돼서 매일 밤 악몽을 꿔
this may end up a cold case.
이것은 미해결 사건으로 끝날 수 있습니다.
I think the world is becoming strange.
세상이 이상해지는 것 같아요.
Seriously.
진지하게.
I feel like I'm running in circles.
나는 원을 그리며 달리는 것 같은 느낌이 듭니다.
What does he want to nag about now?
그 사람은 지금 무슨 잔소리를 하고 싶은 걸까?
Yes?
예?
Where are you, Young-soo? Hurry up and come in.
영수야, 어디 있어? 서둘러서 들어가세요.
-Why? -I think we caught that bastard.
-왜? -우리가 그 새끼를 잡은 것 같아요.
"That bastard"? Which one?
"그 놈"? 어느 것?
That bastard forged your ID card.
그 새끼가 네 신분증을 위조한 거야.
Forged ID card? What are you talking about?
위조된 신분증? 무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
The one I lost four years ago?
내가 4년 전에 잃어버린 그 사람?
Damn it! Just shut up and come.
젠장! 그냥 닥치고 오세요.
The serial killer of the wealthy senior citizen case…
노인부자 사건의 연쇄살인범 ???
We caught that scum!
우리가 그 쓰레기를 잡았어요!
Turn the car around, Ha-young.
차 돌려, 하영아.
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
PERSONAL INFORMATION
개인 정보
You arrested him as a suspect of a sex worker's abduction?
그를 성노동자 납치 용의자로 체포했다고요 ?
Yes.
예.
The women on the staff couldn't be reached.
여자 직원은 연락이 닿지 않았습니다.
The pimp reported him after much suspicion.
포주는 많은 의심 끝에 그를 신고했습니다.
He was arrested around 5:30 a.m. today.
그는 오늘 오전 5시 30분쯤 체포됐다.
Mapo Police Station is done investigating
마포경찰서는 수사를 마쳤다
culprit Gu Young-chun's phone,
범인 구영춘의 휴대폰,
as well as articles from the missing women.
실종 여성들의 기사도 마찬가지다 .
We're also searching through the car of the victim
피해자 차량 도 수색 중
who went missing two days ago.
이틀 전에 실종된 사람이에요.
What about the missing victims?
실종된 피해자들은 어떻습니까?
"I killed them. I didn't."
"내가 그들을 죽였어. 난 안 죽였어."
"I buried them. I didn't."
"나는 그것들을 묻었습니다. 나는 묻지 않았습니다."
His statement is inconsistent.
그의 진술은 일관성이 없습니다.
Anyway, how did Chief Kim Bong-sik
그나저나 김봉식 실장님은 어떻게 됐나요?
end up catching him too?
결국 그 사람도 잡게 되나요?
The owner of the business, Kwak Man-hyun,
업주 곽만현씨.
is an acquaintance of Chief Kim Bong-sik.
김봉식 과장의 지인이다.
That's why he's not showing up?
그래서 그 사람이 나타나지 않는 걸까요?
Anyway,
그래도,
are you sure that guy said he did all those things
그 사람이 그 모든 일을 했다고 말한 게 확실해요?
to the elderly people?
노인들한테?
Yes, I think so.
네, 그런 것 같아요.
But he kept going off speaking nonsense
그런데 그 사람은 계속 말도 안 되는 소리를 하더군요.
on our way here.
여기로 오는 길에.
What do you think, Inspector Song?
송 경위는 어떻게 생각하시나요?
We should check
우리는 확인해야
if he's mentally ill or has personality disorders.
정신적으로 아프 거나 성격 장애가 있는 경우.